[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c072", "question": "What is the Shaddock a variety of?\u00a0", "answer": "Citrus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ef", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows\" what does the acronym RAB stand for?", "answer": "Regulus A. Black", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefc3dd6ce05a3942286f28", "question": "Which member of Fleetwood Mac was inducted into the Rock & Roll Hall of Fame twice?", "answer": "Stevie Nicks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fcb", "question": "What movie featured the fictional band \"The Soggy Bottom Boys\"?", "answer": "O Brother, Where Art Thou?", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c90a", "question": "Which continent is the natural habitat of the Ostrich?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abb8", "question": "Lilongwe is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Malawi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e5", "question": "What is known as a \"Magnum Opus\"?", "answer": "The greatest, most popular or most renowned achievement of a writer, artist or composer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc262ec223966ae8f8874", "question": "What movie star uses his middle initial, B, for \"Bakari\", to avoid confusion with a retired basketball star?", "answer": "Michael B. Jordan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febbc737e83c707845b214c", "question": "Which band's debut album was entitled \"Appetite for Destruction\"?", "answer": "Guns N' Roses'", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b07", "question": "What is the name of the Wally World mascot in \"National Lampoon's Vacation\"?", "answer": "Marty Moose", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa39b4c73aa70ea0b70ada", "question": "Which country does Denmark share its only land border with?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393b4", "question": "Who won an Oscar for her performance in \"Mary Poppins\"?", "answer": "Julie Andrews", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6e4", "question": "What is the shape of a carpenter's square, found in home workshops?", "answer": "L-shape", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6b1", "question": "In NATO's phonetic alphabet, what is the letter \"F\" referred to as?", "answer": "Foxtrot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a626", "question": "Which is the westernmost state in the US?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab1b7fbaab681b0929219a", "question": "What is BMW's name short for?", "answer": "Bayerische Motoren Werke", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa01", "question": "What country celebrates its National Day on 17th May?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339156", "question": "Who said: \"We are more popular than Jesus\"?", "answer": "John Lennon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b7abc6f6490a8cc1a6e529a", "question": "What does the \"c\" in \"E=mc\u00b2\" represent?", "answer": "The speed of light", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdab", "question": "What British actor founded the London Centre for Stammering Children?", "answer": "Michael Palin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b01", "question": "What is the name of the crab who looks after Ariel in Disney's \"The Little Mermaid\"?", "answer": "Sebastian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fab", "question": "What novel was originally released under the title \"The Wild Palms\"?", "answer": "If I Forget Thee, Jerusalem", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d47088f8e329de4f877892", "question": "What is a Winter Banana?", "answer": "A variety of apple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59bb2911c9bff04efae6d754", "question": "In what 1967 film did Gene Hackman earn his first Oscar nomination?", "answer": "Bonnie and Clyde", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6b28dfb6c85e9e634ff3f", "question": "Which years did Henry VI reign England?", "answer": "1422 to 1461 and 1470 to 1471", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad52", "question": "What was the real first name of the First Lady known as Mamie Eisenhower?", "answer": "Mary", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a48b", "question": "In which city is the Prado art gallery located?", "answer": "Madrid", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7cb", "question": "What is Nike's signature symbol called?", "answer": "The swoosh", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a76", "question": "On \"Sesame Street\", which two characters live in an apartment at 123 Sesame Street?", "answer": "Bert and Ernie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5fb", "question": "Which is the biggest planet in our Solar System?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff2114f31a458464a93c440", "question": "Emily Bronte\u2019s \"Wuthering Heights\" famously described which English naturescape?", "answer": "Yorkshire moorlands", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e6a", "question": "What does Miss Havisham constantly wear in Dickens' \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Her wedding dress", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c578fbde8045e48466ad", "question": "A group of otters is called what?", "answer": "A raft", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ded251ea2747c8aff16d3c", "question": "What structure in the back of the brain governs motor control?", "answer": "Cerebellum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396b3", "question": "What Scottish hero did Mel Gibson portray in the 1995 movie \"Braveheart\"?", "answer": "William Wallace", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc8421e78d18506ae1fe48a", "question": "What is the name of the tallest tree in the world?", "answer": "Hyperion", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff2594031a458464a93c46b", "question": "How many years are in a \"score\"?", "answer": "Twenty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a79", "question": "What city does Jackie Moon's team play for in the 2008 movie \"Semi-Pro\"?", "answer": "Flint, Michigan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a213", "question": "What cartoon, from the Talkertoon series, marked the first appearance of Betty Boop?", "answer": "Dizzy Dishes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a57220565ad31a57c7cc", "question": "In which ancient culture were turkeys believed to be gods?", "answer": "Maya", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9f4", "question": "What Mojave Desert city has a name meaning \"the meadows\" in Spanish?", "answer": "Las Vegas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af98453aeb0982ee455954b", "question": "A nonagon is a shape that has how many sides?", "answer": "9", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba24", "question": "How many World Professional Snooker championships did Joe Davis win?", "answer": "15", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc81", "question": "In 1964, who founded Blue Ribbon Sports, which later went on to become Nike?", "answer": "Phil Knight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d07", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Garth Algar?", "answer": "Wayne Campbell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b93", "question": "Who is Becky Thatcher's boyfriend?", "answer": "Tom Sawyer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febd3b97e83c707845b2154", "question": "How many noble houses of Westeros are there in \"Game of Thrones\"?", "answer": "Nine (Arryn, Baratheon, Greyjoy, Lannister, Martell, Stark, Targaryen, Tully and Tyrell)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a552ee3e1c6f9840ba319e", "question": "On the 1976 release, who wanted to \"Fly Like an Eagle\"?", "answer": "Steve Miller Band", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133970f", "question": "In which decade did John Travolta star in \"Grease\"?", "answer": "1970s", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae6e", "question": "What parade first wound through New Orleans streets in 1838?", "answer": "Mardi Gras Parade", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a89d", "question": "In what modern day country was Dalmatia located?", "answer": "Croatia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec8a6fec223966ae8f8831", "question": "In the movie \"Polar Express\", there is one rule when it comes to hot chocolate. What is it?", "answer": "Don't let it cool", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc6a", "question": "How many Super Bowl appearances did Brett Favre lead as part of the Green Bay Packers?", "answer": "2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca3b", "question": "Which element appears seventh on the periodic table?", "answer": "Nitrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b8", "question": "In The Simpsons, who said: \"I thought I'd get into shape, so i've been drinking nothing but milkshakes.\"?", "answer": "Krusty the Clown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6f1", "question": "Salton Sea is located in which western US state?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e046fe83fe1f2a824b89", "question": "What U.S. President refused to use the telephone while in office?", "answer": "Calvin Coolidge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e2", "question": "Who is the director of the movie \"Jurassic Park\"?", "answer": "Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a23a", "question": "What Australian rock band release the album \"Business as Usual\" in 1981?", "answer": "Men at Work", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f564d533a95c66dc4fe752", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed \"Keystone state\"?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b210", "question": "Who was assassinated by Charlotte Corday?", "answer": "Jean-Paul Marat", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396e8", "question": "In what city is Jim Morrison buried?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b02c", "question": "By marrying Prince Rainier, Grace Kelly became princess of what nation?", "answer": "Monaco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339703", "question": "In which country is the musical and film \"Mamma Mia\" set?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388c4", "question": "Who wielded a sword named Excalibur?", "answer": "King Arthur", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b06e", "question": "What was the infamous pseudonym of William Bonney?", "answer": "Billy the Kid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f164fd4f9b80650dbe7f93a", "question": "Who wrote the young adult novel \"Holes\"?", "answer": "Louis Sachar", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a229", "question": "What year marked the release of  Puff Daddy's song \"I'll Be Missing You\"?", "answer": "1997", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffcfbe89dc5ec6cd98a8319", "question": "Who painted The Son of Man?", "answer": "Ren\u00e9 Magritte (The surrealist intended\u00a0the painting\u00a0of a man whose face is obscured by a hovering green apple as a self-portrait.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8b7", "question": "What New York cardiologist published his bestselling \"Diet Revolution\" in 1972?", "answer": "Robert Atkins", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339165", "question": "What is the model name and number of the spacecraft's computer in \"2001: A Space Odyssey\"?", "answer": "HAL 9000", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062a19c9d816e292245c13", "question": "What Flemish Baroque painter is well known for his Counter-Reformation altarpieces?", "answer": "Peter Paul Rubens -- He was a proponent of an extravagant Baroque style that emphasized movement, colour, and sensuality.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b94e", "question": "What common legal item literally means \"under penalty\"?", "answer": "Subpoena", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d9f", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Mars Attacks!\"?", "answer": "Jack Nicholson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392d0", "question": "Whitney Houston and Mariah Carey collaborated on the hit single \"When You Believe\" for what 1998 film?", "answer": "The Prince of Egypt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fde50efc6c6b019850c9a8b", "question": "In the Bible, what does Gideon's name mean?", "answer": "Tree cutter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be70", "question": "What is Michigan Stadium also known as?", "answer": "The Big House", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa25", "question": "What is the principle language of Brazil?", "answer": "Portuguese\u00a0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff517fcff04d658268c92fe", "question": "By which nickname is Henry McCarty better known?", "answer": "Billy the Kid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea7791ff048f679a45abca", "question": "How many watts is one horsepower?", "answer": "746", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae99", "question": "Established in 1607, what settlement was founded by John Smith in Virginia?", "answer": "Jamestown", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c815", "question": "What Italian physician was the first to describe the way the ovaries connect to the uterus in humans?", "answer": "Gabriele Falloppio", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a76", "question": "What was the name of the lead character in the novel \"The Scarlet Letter\"?", "answer": "Hester Prynne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fde4e82c6c6b019850c9a84", "question": "November 11, 1921 marked the first anonymous burial at what famous U.S. cemetery?", "answer": "Arlington National Cemetery", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7a9", "question": "What color appears in the middle of a rainbow?", "answer": "Green", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f7", "question": "What is the longest running event in a decathlon?", "answer": "1500 meters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c261877e98cb97778989", "question": "Where can you find an underwater volcano called \"Kick 'em Jenny\"?", "answer": "Caribbean Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e02", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek goddess Eris?", "answer": "Discordia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fb08768cf631c2414a13b57", "question": "In \"Game of Thrones\", what are the three names of Daenerys\u2019 dragons?", "answer": "Drogon, Viserion, and Rhaegal", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5937ec9d08d98002fdd633bd", "question": "Equatorial Guinea gained independence from which country in 1968?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ec26928dc25ca9e12ef64d", "question": "How many engines does the B-52 bomber have?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd02", "question": "Who launched her signature fragrance, \"Moi\", in 1998?", "answer": "Miss Piggy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ffb", "question": "Who was the son of Saturn and Ops, and the husband of Juno?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339adc", "question": "What was the name of the middle Tanner daughter on \"Full House\"?", "answer": "Stephanie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339881", "question": "In Star Wars, which actor voiced Darth Vader?", "answer": "James Earl Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3de2ff048f679a45ab55", "question": "What do insects take oxygen through?", "answer": "Spiracles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd96ecf23c87fd04dd15e3d", "question": "Who founded the Church of Scientology?", "answer": "L. Ron Hubbard", "category": "history"}, {"id": "593c49fbb8198b9a2b077959", "question": "In which film did Brad Pitt play the role of Mickey O'Neil?", "answer": "Snatch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adb4", "question": "Kim Campbell was the leader of what country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f77", "question": "Which American author wrote \"Moby Dick\"?", "answer": "Herman Melville", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c146", "question": "How many dots are there on a die?", "answer": "21", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c4", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize for discovering Penicillin?", "answer": "Alexander Fleming", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9f24eff048f679a45aab8", "question": "What type of cloud is often described as \"cotton-like\"?", "answer": "Cumulus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a24d", "question": "What year did Huey Lewis and the News record the song \"Jacob's Ladder\"?", "answer": "1986", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cda", "question": "What British statesman wrote \"A History of the English-Speaking People\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "594d07e91a1c922dd1ac64bd", "question": "Which Science Fiction author wrote \"The Day of the Triffids\"?", "answer": "John Wyndham", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1a6", "question": "What was Betty Rubble's maiden name?", "answer": "McBricker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa32", "question": "In which country is Cusco located?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8b5", "question": "Proteus orbits what planet of the solar system?", "answer": "Neptune", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b94d", "question": "What is the American equivalent of the Irish Poteen?", "answer": "Moonshine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ed", "question": "Thimpu is the capital of what tiny kingdom?", "answer": "Bhutan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be5b", "question": "What rock band brought suit in 1994 claiming that Ticketmaster was an illegal monopoly?", "answer": "Pearl Jam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c587", "question": "What type of plant is a Saguaro?", "answer": "Cactus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5feddf166ce05a3942286dae", "question": "In which year was Tiger Woods named the PGA Tour Rookie of the Year?", "answer": "1996", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6017382d44491cbd7c5a1795", "question": "What was the first U.S. state to ban billboards?", "answer": "Hawaii -- Billboards were banned in Hawaii in 1927.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2a6", "question": "How many grams is 1 Troy Ounce?", "answer": "31.1 grams", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6008e036f4f3bc4a292f8630", "question": "Who said, \"No one can make you feel inferior without your consent\"?", "answer": "Eleanor Roosevelt (The wife of President Franklin Roosevelt was a political force in her own right.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ef4", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Bigger Thomas?", "answer": "Native Son", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b45", "question": "What does the Giant smell when he says \"Fee, Fi, Foe, Fum\"?", "answer": "The blood of an Englishman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a31f", "question": "Who plays the role of the Prime Minister, in the 2003 film \"Love Actually\"?", "answer": "Hugh Grant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a45d", "question": "The island country Grenada is also known as what?", "answer": "Island of Spice", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388c6", "question": "What is considered the sister language of English?", "answer": "German", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2ba", "question": "Which of Henry VIII's wives was German?", "answer": "Anne of Cleves", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b7abce66490a8cc1a6e529c", "question": "In The Maze Runner, what does \"WICKED\" stand for?", "answer": "World In Catastrophe: Killzone Experiment Department", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4e2", "question": "Which country covers an entire continent?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a899c4760d398dc9cf7a6a7", "question": "Hestia is the daughter of which two titans?", "answer": "Cronus and Rhea", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "594a61ca2ebb971c1417fb8a", "question": "By what name is \"One Thousand and One Nights\" better known as in the English language?", "answer": "Arabian Nights", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60062d9ac9d816e292245c35", "question": "Who painted \"The Scream\"?", "answer": "Edvard Munch\u00a0painted \"The Scream.\"  His style is recognized by most critics as leading to the birth of German Expressionism.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c408877e98cb97778999", "question": "What is the highest waterfall in Africa?", "answer": "Tugela Falls", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c927fbde8045e48466e8", "question": "Holstein, Jersey, and Highland are all breeds of which farm animal?", "answer": "Cows -- There are more than 70 cattle breeds in the US alone and over 250 in the world.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f3", "question": "What is Tchaikovsky's ballet \"Le Lac des Cygnes\" commonly called?", "answer": "Swan Lake", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad8", "question": "What soft drink, introduced in 1982, was the number three US seller within two years?", "answer": "Diet Coke", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa4102c73aa70ea0b70b0e", "question": "What tiny island makes the curling stones used in the Olympics?", "answer": "Ailsa Craig, Scotland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594d07341a1c922dd1ac64b6", "question": "Who was first to voice Porky Pig from 1935 to 1937?", "answer": "Joe Dougherty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf82", "question": "What country celebrates its National Day on 14th July?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aabf", "question": "Which Canadian island is named after the father of Queen Victoria?", "answer": "Prince Edward Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b6992b1e762b54eb9be9425", "question": "Which chemical element\u2019s atomic number is 20?", "answer": "Calcium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0b4", "question": "What is the name of the reverend who appears in the cartoon series \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Timothy Lovejoy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f956fe83fe1f2a824c32", "question": "In which country was St. Patrick born?", "answer": "Britain. Despite being the main and foremost patron saint of Ireland, Saint Patrick wasn't actually born in Ireland.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e5f", "question": "According to the poem, how many spectators saw Mighty Casey strike out?", "answer": "Five thousand", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa5b", "question": "Port Vila is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Vanuatu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac04", "question": "Yaren is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Nauru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff6684352a821ff76ae8b02", "question": "What is the name of the food that was miraculously provided to the desert-dwelling Israelites of the Old Testament?", "answer": "Manna", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d2e", "question": "What is Biff's last name in the \"Back to the Future\" movies?", "answer": "Tannen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8e1", "question": "What California region includes Alameda and Contra Costa counties?", "answer": "East Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe65689ae7e414034b5aecb", "question": "What year did the Battle of Agincourt take place?", "answer": "1415", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb85", "question": "What businessman served as manager of the Atlanta Braves for one game in 1977?", "answer": "Ted Turner", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c209", "question": "Which country were the 1912 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c7c", "question": "What is Indiana Jones' daytime occupation?", "answer": "Professor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e58", "question": "What literary work inspired Nirvana's \"Scentless Apprentice\" song?", "answer": "Perfume", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba34", "question": "What team did hall-of-fame catcher Johnny Bench play for?", "answer": "Cincinnati Reds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c76d", "question": "What type of skin cancer starts in the pigment cells, often after too much sun exposure?", "answer": "Melanoma", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1dd", "question": "What does the term \"A La Carte\" literally translate to in English?", "answer": "According to the menu", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f08c01dd7bf43be5e7fe", "question": "What is the key difference between pizza and flatbread?", "answer": "Yeast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af0b", "question": "During what century was the Mexican War fought?", "answer": "19th Century", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe69ccc20565ad31a57c76f", "question": "Who was the captain of the \"Mayflower\"?", "answer": "Christopher Jones", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe76bbceec85e375820b2c8", "question": "Where is the world\u2019s largest Buddhist temple?", "answer": "Borobudur, Indonesia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa47", "question": "What is the principal river of Ireland?", "answer": "River Shannon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071dcc3745b36be73039dd", "question": "What is the nationality of the first woman in space?", "answer": "Soviet/Russian", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baeb", "question": "What is the traditional decorative sash worn around the middle of a Japanese kimono called?", "answer": "Obi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc1226ce05a3942286f0f", "question": "In the film \"The Bourne Ultimatum,\" where is the \"Treadstone\" facility located?", "answer": "415 East 71st Street, NYC", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b22", "question": "When it debuted, what FOX series was promoted as a \"weekly nationwide criminal manhunt\"?", "answer": "America's Most Wanted", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae97", "question": "To what tribe did Sitting Bull belong?", "answer": "Sioux", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec87faec223966ae8f881a", "question": "Which band saw its original members reunited for the first time in 24 years during the 2005 Live 8 concert in London?", "answer": "Pink Floyd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d68", "question": "In the Bible, who is the mother of the prophet Samuel?", "answer": "Hannah", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ab15dabaab681b0929217e", "question": "What was the world\u2019s first mass-produced car to feature an all-aluminium body?", "answer": "Honda NSX", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d2db2596a59cbdfbd394", "question": "The Iguazu Falls lie on the border of Brazil and which country?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133996d", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", whose mother did Comic Book Guy once date?", "answer": "Principal Skinner's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2d7", "question": "Who were Bobby Hatfield and Bill Medley?", "answer": "The Righteous Brothers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51bddff04d658268c9311", "question": "In the Bible, who sold his birthright because he was hungry?", "answer": "Esau", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c036", "question": "What are Limerick, Round Bend, Aberdeen and Octopus?", "answer": "Fishing hooks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a75", "question": "For what 1997 film did Demi Moore shave her head?", "answer": "G.I. Jane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7e7", "question": "What company produced the first computer to run a Microsoft operating system?", "answer": "IBM", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a30220565ad31a57c7b0", "question": "What did the letters on the first license plates represent?", "answer": "The owner's initials", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecd3aeec223966ae8f88c7", "question": "Who was the first person to accrue ten Academy Award nominations for acting?", "answer": "Bette Davis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc2dcec223966ae8f8878", "question": "What comedy became the first film directed by a woman to gross over $100 million at the US box office?", "answer": "\"Big\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339397", "question": "What is Private Ryan's first name?", "answer": "James", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60077fd2bd51d85e222ab640", "question": "What was the official diagnosis when van Gogh was hospitalized in 1888?", "answer": "When Van Gogh was hospitalized on Christmas Eve 1888 in Ales, his official diagnosis was \"acute mania with generalised delirium\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b37f", "question": "Tchaikovsky is considered to have died of which disease?", "answer": "Cholera", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339852", "question": "In \"Spirited Away\", what name does Yubaba give to Chihiro?", "answer": "Sen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc0a", "question": "Hockey player Wayne Gretzky was born in what Canadian city?", "answer": "Brantford, Ontario", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65f131f3c0ead6880d634", "question": "In ancient Greece, throwing an apple at someone was a declaration of what?", "answer": "Love", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af34", "question": "Which treaty ended the war between Germany and the Allied Powers in World War I?", "answer": "Treaty of Versailles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8a0aec223966ae8f882d", "question": "What was the first animated film to be nominated for Best Picture at the Academy Awards?", "answer": "\"Beauty and the Beast\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0a9", "question": "What island nation was ruled by \"Papa Doc\" and \"Baby Doc\" Duvalier?", "answer": "Haiti", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f65", "question": "Gene Kelly sings \"Singin' in the Rain\" over the end credits of what 1971 movie?", "answer": "A Clockwork Orange", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c086", "question": "In 1917 Lucy Slowe was the first US what?", "answer": "African-American tennis champion", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4ad", "question": "Which country were the 1952 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1c9", "question": "What are the three primary ingredients in a standard Grasshopper cocktail?", "answer": "Creme de Menthe, Creme de Cacao and fresh cream", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f6dcff048f679a45aadf", "question": "What is Johannes Kepler best known for?", "answer": "Kepler's laws of planetary motion", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015eba4fe83fe1f2a824bf9", "question": "In what country was the phrase \"trick or treat\" first used?", "answer": "Canada -- The first recorded use of the term was in 1927 in Lethbridge, Alberta.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601370cb1381754895396385", "question": "The Blondie song \"Call Me\" is featured in what movie?", "answer": "\"American Gigolo\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0aa", "question": "Who won an oscar for her role in \"Gone with the Wind\"?", "answer": "Vivien Leigh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c372", "question": "How many carats is pure gold?", "answer": "24", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b8d4ec2b42d4a3561a9efd", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what is Darcy Parker\u2019s alias?", "answer": "Darcia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffcfea99dc5ec6cd98a832b", "question": "What word did Robert A. Heinlein introduce into the English language in his book \"Stranger in a Strange Land\"?", "answer": "In the 1961 science-fiction novel, Heinlein coined the term Grok, which means \"to understand intuitively or by empathy\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f9f3f7caf848b908361b86c", "question": "What do the numbers on a roulette wheel add up to?", "answer": "666", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a3", "question": "What color is Shrek?", "answer": "Green", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd82403d0de9af39e9d46b6", "question": "What year did Washington, D.C., become the U.S. capital?", "answer": "1790", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a6b720565ad31a57c7dd", "question": "The aircraft carrier USS Lexington was lost in which World War II battle?", "answer": "The Battle of the Coral Sea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6a8", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Pelican State\"?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b48c149076251badbeaa6", "question": "Who was the first sitting member of the U.S. Congress to travel in space?", "answer": "In 1985, Senator Jake Garn went into space aboard Space Shuttle\u00a0Discovery's STS-51-D mission as a payload specialist.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133960a", "question": "Who directed the 1994 movie \"True Lies\"?", "answer": "James Cameron", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e016fe83fe1f2a824b86", "question": "Who was the first to accurately describe the human circulatory system?", "answer": "William Harvey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a05720565ad31a57c794", "question": "What historical ruler instituted one of the first international postal services?", "answer": "Genghis Khan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a70", "question": "Who has a heart \"two sizes too small\"?", "answer": "The Grinch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b070", "question": "Who the first American World Chess Champion?", "answer": "Bobby Fisher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338906", "question": "Who wrote the music for the stage version of \"Billy Elliot\"?", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adb9", "question": "Who was crowned King of England on December 25, 1066?", "answer": "William the Conqueror", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ac1", "question": "Where do \"Harold and Kumar Escape From...\" in their 2008 movie sequel?", "answer": "Guantanamo Bay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397d6", "question": "Who created the original Star Trek series?", "answer": "Gene Roddenberry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f92", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"Alfie\"?", "answer": "Vivien Merchant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3c6eff048f679a45ab3d", "question": "Catagelophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Being ridiculed", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1bf", "question": "What year did Ferdinand Porsche and his team started to design the VW Beetle?", "answer": "1934", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5f6", "question": "What is the shape of the goat's pupil?", "answer": "Horizontal slit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b22c", "question": "Where did Al Capone spend the majority of his 1931 sentence for tax evasion?", "answer": "Alcatraz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b225", "question": "In which city was American actor Bob Crane murdered?", "answer": "Scottsdale, Arizona", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59636e8e967692ea851899b3", "question": "On average, we spend 6 months of our lives waiting for what?", "answer": "Traffic lights to change", "category": "general"}, {"id": "591c3631815febcc896f9265", "question": "Which actor took the male lead in Hitchcock's film \"The Birds\"?", "answer": "Rod Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d2a92596a59cbdfbd391", "question": "Equity State is the official nickname of which state?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133987a", "question": "In Star Wars, where is Princess Leia from?", "answer": "Alderaan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac06", "question": "What was the Republic of Nauru previously known as?", "answer": "Pleasant Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59523c9d736d4be723796b39", "question": "What are Canada\u2019s two official sports?", "answer": "Ice hockey and lacrosse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394f1", "question": "Who made his directorial debut with the 1966 movie \"Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf\"?", "answer": "Mike Nichols", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea462cff048f679a45ab9f", "question": "Which fruit is also known as \"courgette\"?", "answer": "Zucchini", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa4a56ce05a3942286eb6", "question": "What is the name of the cat in the film \"Hocus Pocus\"?", "answer": "Thackery Binx", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb67c75dad637d903c883e", "question": "Mauritius is the only African country where the most commonly practised religion is what?", "answer": "Hinduism", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600241334be4723ccac22172", "question": "A painting by what artist was once mistakenly hung upside-down at MoMA?", "answer": "Henri Matisse -- A stock broker, familiar with Matisse's work, noticed \u201cLe Bateau\u201d was hanging upside down at the museum in NYC.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef65ff6ce05a3942286e73", "question": "Which famous actress was the first Tool Time Girl on \"Home Improvement\"?", "answer": "Pamela Anderson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d35", "question": "Who's responsible for performing \"The Ballad of The Green Berets\"?", "answer": "Barry Sadler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7354beec85e375820b248", "question": "Who said, \u201cThere are a terrible lot of lies going about the world, and the worst of it is that half of them are true.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea46efff048f679a45aba6", "question": "What is the layer in the earth's atmosphere at 15-30 km altitude called in scientific terms?", "answer": "Ozone layer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b566", "question": "What color moves first in checkers?", "answer": "Black", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339145", "question": "Thomas Mann's novella \"Der Tod in Venedig\" is better known under which English title?", "answer": "Death in Venice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133901b", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Valley of the Dolls\"?", "answer": "Jacqueline Susann", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b561", "question": "What three colours does Asparagus come in?", "answer": "Green, White, Purple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b362", "question": "What was unusual about Tyrell's car in the 1976 Swedish Grand Prix?", "answer": "It had six wheels", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339491", "question": "What highway were Mickey and Mallory travelling in the movie \"Natural Born Killers\"?", "answer": "Highway 666", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f721aa9e54d890926f6ea", "question": "In which ocean can you find Australia\u2019s Great Barrier Reef?", "answer": "Pacific -- It is comprised of over 3,000 reef systems and contains over 400 different types of coral and is visible from space.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef65db6ce05a3942286e72", "question": "Who delivers the high-school commencement speech in \"Boy Meets World\"?", "answer": "Shawn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c465", "question": "What does a pluviometer measure?", "answer": "Rainfall", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398b2", "question": "Who played the role of an eccentric inventor in the movie \"Chitty Chitty Bang Bang\"?", "answer": "Dick Van Dyke", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a69", "question": "The line \"I never saw a purple cow\" is the beginning of a poem by what author?", "answer": "Gelett Burgess", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9b8", "question": "How many hearts does an octopus have?\u00a0", "answer": "Three hearts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339201", "question": "In what movie does Redfoot flick his cigarette into the face of McManus?", "answer": "The Usual Suspects", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a208", "question": "What is singer Wynonna Judd's real name?", "answer": "Christina Clair Ciminella", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b88a01dd7bf43be5e7ec", "question": "Vultures gathering on the side of the road to eat are called what?", "answer": "A wake", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d7", "question": "Who traditionally occupied the Peacock Throne?", "answer": "The shah of Iran", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f16ae3f7c52aae91cc07e2", "question": "What sort of food are \"rollmops\"?", "answer": "Fish", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133983a", "question": "Who won a Grammy Award for his album \"Come Dance With Me\"?", "answer": "Frank Sinatra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7d0", "question": "Which chemical element did the ancients call brimstone?", "answer": "Sulfur", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9c6", "question": "What disease is considered the human form of \"Mad Cow's Disease\"?", "answer": "Creutzfeldt-Jakobs Disease", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f56", "question": "In one myth, what dance was first performed by Hi'iaka to appease the volcano goddess, Pele?", "answer": "The hula", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6be", "question": "What bird has the largest beak relative to its body size?", "answer": "The Toucan", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5f9f4648af848b908361b875", "question": "Should the cream or jam be spread first, if you are to use the \"Cornish method\"?", "answer": "Jam then cream", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abf8", "question": "In France what is a Framboise?", "answer": "Raspberry", "category": "geography"}]